<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-20T21:53:27+00:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Giving $10</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Project 2012 2</title><link href="/projects-2012/2012/02/29/project-2012-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project 2012 2" /><published>2012-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-02-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2012/2012/02/29/project-2012-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2012/2012/02/29/project-2012-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your February 2012 report for The $10 Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since 1996, the Visakha Society for the Protection and Care of Animals (VSPCA) has worked to improve the conditions for animals in India, protecting endangered sea turtles, rescuing cows, and providing housing to dogs, cats, and other animals in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout India, there is a connection between stray dogs and cats and impoverished people living on the streets. Homeless people in India might be emotionally traumatized, mentally disabled, or in other ways infirm. The bond these people develop with animals is strong and often an easier relationship than would be possible with people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Pradeep Kumar Nath, VSPCA's Founder and President: &quot;In reality they are seeking each other's company to strike a bond of love and affection after being abandoned by their own society and now are building a relationship of life. ... a life is a life and is not related to physical appearance.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January 2010, VSPCA began a plan to deliver vegan meals to India's poor humans living on the streets. Called the &quot;Kindness Mobile Restaurant,&quot; roughly eighty people are served weekly in three different areas. A wholesome and nutritious vegan meal (lentils, vegetable curry, fruit and one sachet of drinking water) is hygienically packed in palm leaves and provided by auto-rickshaw to the poorest of the poor three days a week (when other charities in the area are not operating).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Giving $10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, 246 of us joined together to donate $2,460 to the Visakha Society for the Protection and Care of Animals in India to provide 5,000 food packets to homeless people in need serving dozens of people three times a week for an entire year. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nath writes: &quot;Every one of them has a trusted association with a street dog. They give the first morsel of food to the dog that comes at that time to get their first share. Both the poor person and the street dog have both overcome loneliness in having each other as companions.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;India has some 1.2 billion people, 30% of whom live in urban areas. 237 million people or one in five are malnourished. Nearly half of India's children are malnourished to the point of being underweight and having their growth stunted. The breadth of the problem is overwhelming. But for about 80 of the poorest of the poor in the country, for the rest of the year, food insecurity will not be a problem thanks to your small sacrifice this month!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving the world, ten dollars at a time,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects-2012" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Project 2012 1</title><link href="/projects-2012/2012/01/31/project-2012-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project 2012 1" /><published>2012-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2012-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2012/2012/01/31/project-2012-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2012/2012/01/31/project-2012-1.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your January 2012 report for Giving $10.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1956, the mission of Hôpital Albert Schweitzer Haiti (HAS) has been to collaborate with the people of the Artibonite Valley as they strive to improve their health and quality of life. Thanks to HAS, district residents even in the remote mountains can find health care within reach and at an affordable cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address the root causes of diarrhea and malnutrition, and now cholera which emerged in epidemic proportions in Haiti in 2010, HAS has focused on community health and development activities, including drilling wells and providing sanitation, which have allowed many families to have access to clean drinking water and latrines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pont Sondé is a key market and transport hub at the edge of the HAS district. The local economy revolves around transportation, commodity marketing, and rice. Roughly 4,000 people live in the in-district parts of Pont Sondé, with many more in the adjacent parts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geologically the area is challenging, with salt deposits in the alluvial sand and gravel underlying much of the area. Potable groundwater sits in a lens on saline water, and in some areas is at risk of contamination by fertilizers used in the many nearby rice fields. Residents must get their water either from shallow wells or from rainwater capture. Thus, this area has a high need for at-home water treatment to ensure that contaminants are removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HAS has been building and installing thousands of Biosand filters in the past decade, allowing more than 15,000 people to have access to potable drinking and wash water. The Biosand technology is very practical. Users do not need great skill to use it and necessary maintenance is easy to do, making the Biosand filter very suitable for the rural environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Giving $10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, 225 of us joined together to donate $2,250 to HAS to install nearly 50 new filters in high-need households in the Pont Sondé area in the Artibonite Valley of Haiti. They will undertake spot-testing of water quality to identify particularly high-need households and provide the community with education in potable water, sanitation, and hygiene. A local mason will be contracted to produce, deliver, and install the filters and an HAS mason technician will ensure the quality control of construction and installation. He will also train residents in filter use and maintenance. Recipient families will visited later to make sure each water filter continues to work and receives proper maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water filters stave off dehydration - a leading cause of death among Haitian children under the age of five - as well as gastrointestinal disease. These simple Biosand units filter out up to 95% or more bacteria and virtually 100% of larger organisms, particularly giardia and other cysts which are resistant to chlorine. The end result will be drinking, cooking, and bathing water that meets water quality standards for hundreds of people at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saving the world, ten dollars at a time,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects-2012" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends: Welcome to your January 2012 report for Giving $10. Since 1956, the mission of Hôpital Albert Schweitzer Haiti (HAS) has been to collaborate with the people of the Artibonite Valley as they strive to improve their health and quality of life. Thanks to HAS, district residents even in the remote mountains can find health care within reach and at an affordable cost. To address the root causes of diarrhea and malnutrition, and now cholera which emerged in epidemic proportions in Haiti in 2010, HAS has focused on community health and development activities, including drilling wells and providing sanitation, which have allowed many families to have access to clean drinking water and latrines. Pont Sondé is a key market and transport hub at the edge of the HAS district. The local economy revolves around transportation, commodity marketing, and rice. Roughly 4,000 people live in the in-district parts of Pont Sondé, with many more in the adjacent parts. Geologically the area is challenging, with salt deposits in the alluvial sand and gravel underlying much of the area. Potable groundwater sits in a lens on saline water, and in some areas is at risk of contamination by fertilizers used in the many nearby rice fields. Residents must get their water either from shallow wells or from rainwater capture. Thus, this area has a high need for at-home water treatment to ensure that contaminants are removed. HAS has been building and installing thousands of Biosand filters in the past decade, allowing more than 15,000 people to have access to potable drinking and wash water. The Biosand technology is very practical. Users do not need great skill to use it and necessary maintenance is easy to do, making the Biosand filter very suitable for the rural environment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">$10 Club Receives E Chievement Award</title><link href="/news/2011/10/18/$10-Club-receives-E-Chievement-Award.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="$10 Club Receives E Chievement Award" /><published>2011-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2011/10/18/$10-Club-receives-E-Chievement-Award</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2011/10/18/$10-Club-receives-E-Chievement-Award.html">&lt;p&gt;Adam Roberts and The $10 Club received the eTown E-Chievement award in a special event in Boulder, CO. The event will air across North America on over 300 stations from October 12th-October 19th, depending on the day and time their individual affiliate stations air the show. Many stations also stream over the web, so you can listen from their websites, anywhere in the world. They also podcast the show. Check eTowns website to find out how and where to tune in: http://www.etown.org/listen.php&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-etown&quot;&gt;About eTown&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1991, eTown is a nationally-syndicated radio show heard weekly on over 300 public, community and commercial stations across North America and via podcast. eTown is a nonprofit, 501(c)3 corporation whose mission is to educate, entertain and inspire a diverse audience, through music and conversation, to create a socially responsible and environmentally sustainable world. Every eTown show is taped in front of a live audience, and features performances from many of today’s top musical artists as well as thought-provoking interviews and the presentation of the listener-nominated E-Chievement Award recognizing everyday people who have made a difference in their community or beyond. Founders Nick Forster, of the legendary bluegrass band Hot Rize fame, and his wife, singer/actress Helen Forster host the show. For more information, visit www.etown.org.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-the-e-chievement-award&quot;&gt;About the E-Chievement Award&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the show’s most popular segments is the E-Chievement Award. Listeners from around the country send in nominations of remarkable individuals who are working hard to make a positive difference in their communities and beyond. From massive river clean-ups to programs that help the homeless, from neighborhood activists to national and international social and environmental organizations, eTown takes pride in celebrating the success stories of ordinary citizens accomplishing extraordinary things. To learn more about the E-Chievement Award, visit www.etown.org.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">Adam Roberts and The $10 Club received the eTown E-Chievement award in a special event in Boulder, CO. The event will air across North America on over 300 stations from October 12th-October 19th, depending on the day and time their individual affiliate stations air the show. Many stations also stream over the web, so you can listen from their websites, anywhere in the world. They also podcast the show. Check eTowns website to find out how and where to tune in: http://www.etown.org/listen.php</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Project 2011 2</title><link href="/projects-2011/2011/02/28/project-2011-2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project 2011 2" /><published>2011-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2011/2011/02/28/project-2011-2</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2011/2011/02/28/project-2011-2.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your February 2011 report for The $10 Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eighty per cent of the total land in the Amazon is occupied by indigenous people. Less than 10% have access to safe drinking water and, in the Peruvian Amazon, the lack of potable water has led to various cholera epidemics in the past two decades. Contaminated water and lack of basic sanitation standards are a threat to the indigenous communities in the frontier between Peru and Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dry season of 2010 (September-November) was reported as the most severe of the last 40 years with the Amazon River dropping down to its lowest level. Communities close to the river lacked access to water and faced an alarming sanitary crisis, which exposed local people especially children and the elderly to water-borne diseases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundacion Entropika works on conservation of the region's tropical biodiversity by facilitating local community-led projects and working closely with the local indigenous people to tackle conservation issues. As part of their work they are implementing a campaign to promote sanitation and hygiene to overcome the current cholera epidemic that is affecting the Peruvian Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, 270 of us joined together to donate $2,700 to Fundacion Entropika to provide potable water to an indigenous community in the Peruvian Amazon, specifically for 330 people in the Vista Alegre community. We will fund installation of a tubwell system for pumping water from the Amazon; promote safe use of potable water; increase awareness of the dangers of contaminated water; raise awareness of hygiene and sanitation issues; and ensure safe water to the community. We will specifically fund the purchase of a variety of PVC pipes; ejector valves, wire mesh, gravel, storage tanks, electric pumps, and materials transport to build the wells. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundacion Entropika recently assessed the needs for potable water in each of the communities they serve with the technical assistance of an engineer who has 27 years experience in the installation of water technologies in the Amazon area. The different locations of the communities and their corresponding conditions require different water solutions. Hand pumps were not recommended as they are not reliable during the dry season, at least 5 hand pumps would be required to meet the needs of the whole community during the wet season, and the costs of the hand pumps and their maintenance are high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to you and your donation this month, potable water will be delivered to communities in need in the Peruvian Amazon, well maintenance will be taught, and people will receive much-needed knowledge about water and sanitation issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving the world, ten dollars at a time,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects-2011" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Project 2011 1</title><link href="/projects-2011/2011/01/31/project-2011-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project 2011 1" /><published>2011-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2011-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2011/2011/01/31/project-2011-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2011/2011/01/31/project-2011-1.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your January 2011 project report for Giving $10. I apologize for the delay in submitting this report - it has been a very hectic start to the year. February and March reports will follow soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kilimanjaro Orphanage Center (KOC) in Moshi, Tanzania was founded in early 2009 by Edward Lazaro responding to the recognized need to provide care and shelter to an increasing population of orphaned children in the Moshi area. The Center provides food, clothing, shelter, education, spiritual guidance and medical care to the residents of the facility as well as to other needy children in the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently KOC houses 30 children, mostly between the ages of 4 and 10, at a housing center in Pasua Tanzania a small community just outside of Moshi. The long term vision is to buy and build a preplanned community for up to 100 children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many heart-wrenching and heart-warming stories of the kids there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Agnes, for instance, was under the long standing care of a maternal aunt who never liked her and who prevented her from attending school so that she could work full time in the house caring for the aunt's own children. Both of her parents died from AIDS.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Esther's mother was murdered by her step father who is in prison. It remains unclear whether she has a biologic living father. She came to the orphanage in poor health suffering from malnutrition. She had received no schooling before arriving at the orphanage.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Winifreda was living with an elderly grandmother who was unable to provide for her after the death of her parents from HIV. She has no siblings and she has never had visitors since going to the orphanage. She is a very shy and quiet child, but is very popular with all of the other children. She was one of my bravest children when taken to the dentist for tooth fillings.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Gloria was being cared for on a farm on the slopes of Kilimanjaro by an elderly grandmother who was partially paralyzed by a stroke and by a grandfather who had lost a leg from an infection. Her mother died from HIV in 2005 and her father was never known. She has no brothers or sisters. After a long and tearful meeting with her caregivers who realized that they had little opportunity to offer her, she went to live at the Center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Giving $10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, 250 of us donated $2,500 to the Kilimanjaro Orphanage Center to assist in the acquisition and installation of a solar hot water heater. I'm told this will have an immediate, positive impact on the lives of the children there. It will, of course, provide the children with hot water for regular showers. Further, it will help reduce the risks of several medical problems for the children such as skin diseases and infections. Additionally, cleaning efforts will become far more effective having access to a ready source of hot water, facilitating the fight against the spread of germs and bacteria. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Presumably, we all take access to hot water for granted. For Agnes, Esther, Wini, Gloria, and dozens of other children in Tanzania, it's a previously unknown treat that will improve their health and their lives overall. There is also an economic and environmental impact from our project, which will reduce the monthly overhead costs of heating or boiling water by propane or wood fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Jamie King, the project coordinator:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The solar hot water heater will provide the children with hot water on a daily basis at no cost after the initial set up for at least the next 25 years, something the care givers and physicians are extremely excited about.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for making this happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to give you all an update on the Solar hot water project. After much delay and lots of hard work from Teacher and Greg they finally got the company we purchased the heater from to come back and finish the installation. On behalf of everyone at the orphanage I've been asked to tell you all how happy they are with the system and to thank you. The matrons are singing the praises of the system for how clean the children's clothes are coming as well as how clean the kids are getting. Thank you all so much for your help with this project, for many I know it is hard to visualize the difference you made in the lives of these children but having hot water will help with many of the daily chores that typically require propane or firewood as well as help control many of the skin disease problems that can occur. I have attached pictures of the system and some of it being built and used. We were also able to install several outdoor water hoses and plumb the kitchen, two showers, and a hot water sink outside for all the many chores they use water for. Thank you all for the help and support with this project, please give me a call or shoot me an email if you would like to hear more about the Orphanage and how things are going. - Jamie King&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects-2011" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends: Welcome to your January 2011 project report for Giving $10. I apologize for the delay in submitting this report - it has been a very hectic start to the year. February and March reports will follow soon. The Kilimanjaro Orphanage Center (KOC) in Moshi, Tanzania was founded in early 2009 by Edward Lazaro responding to the recognized need to provide care and shelter to an increasing population of orphaned children in the Moshi area. The Center provides food, clothing, shelter, education, spiritual guidance and medical care to the residents of the facility as well as to other needy children in the community. Currently KOC houses 30 children, mostly between the ages of 4 and 10, at a housing center in Pasua Tanzania a small community just outside of Moshi. The long term vision is to buy and build a preplanned community for up to 100 children. There are so many heart-wrenching and heart-warming stories of the kids there. Agnes, for instance, was under the long standing care of a maternal aunt who never liked her and who prevented her from attending school so that she could work full time in the house caring for the aunt's own children. Both of her parents died from AIDS. Esther's mother was murdered by her step father who is in prison. It remains unclear whether she has a biologic living father. She came to the orphanage in poor health suffering from malnutrition. She had received no schooling before arriving at the orphanage. Winifreda was living with an elderly grandmother who was unable to provide for her after the death of her parents from HIV. She has no siblings and she has never had visitors since going to the orphanage. She is a very shy and quiet child, but is very popular with all of the other children. She was one of my bravest children when taken to the dentist for tooth fillings. Gloria was being cared for on a farm on the slopes of Kilimanjaro by an elderly grandmother who was partially paralyzed by a stroke and by a grandfather who had lost a leg from an infection. Her mother died from HIV in 2005 and her father was never known. She has no brothers or sisters. After a long and tearful meeting with her caregivers who realized that they had little opportunity to offer her, she went to live at the Center.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">$10 Club Highlighted In New Book Our Day To End Poverty</title><link href="/news/2010/10/14/$10-Club-highlighted-in-new-book-Our-Day-to-End-Poverty.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="$10 Club Highlighted In New Book Our Day To End Poverty" /><published>2010-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2010/10/14/$10-Club-highlighted-in-new-book-Our-Day-to-End-Poverty</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2010/10/14/$10-Club-highlighted-in-new-book-Our-Day-to-End-Poverty.html"></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Project 2010 02</title><link href="/projects-2010/2010/02/01/project-2010-02.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project 2010 02" /><published>2010-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2010/2010/02/01/project-2010-02</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2010/2010/02/01/project-2010-02.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your February 2010 report for The $10 Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invariably, after disaster strikes, there is a rush of compassionate people who want to help. This was true after the tsunami devastated portions of Sri Lanka and Thailand, or Hurricane Katrina assaulted New Orleans closer to home. And now, the earthquake in Haiti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But with this outpouring of public support comes the stories of funds not reaching the people on the ground who need it most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In December 2007 we built a road in Haiti to connect a remote and impoverished community with the nearest hospital Hôpital Albert Schweitzer Haiti (HAS). I am informed that the Gabriel-Tienne Road, repaired two years ago with your support, is sturdy and weathered the earthquake with no problems. Knowing that HAS needs aid and that they will put our contribution to good use right away tending to people in emergency need I went back to them to offer our financial relief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, 340 of us joined together to donate $3,400 to Hôpital Albert Schweitzer Haiti to fund the salary of a surgical support staff person ($2,700 per year), as well as $700 toward needed maintenance for surgical equipment such as sterilizers. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAS is one of the few surgical hospitals in Haiti that was able to begin treating earthquake victims within hours of the tragedy. Now that the urgency of traumatic injuries is abating, new challenges are emerging in providing preventive care and health services to hundreds of thousands of displaced Haitians coming from their 610 square mile service area. Tens of thousands of people have arrived. Trauma teams led by Haitian medical personnel doctors and nurses they have trained over the years have been providing life saving care following the earthquake. In two weeks following the earthquake, the hospital treated more than 850 victims, mostly major surgical procedures. This is ten times the normal surgery volume. HAS was one of the very few hospitals able to treat complex injuries immediately following the earthquake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Haiti has faced a number of natural and man-made disasters over the past decade, the recent earthquake is by far the most severe among them. The effects simply have been catastrophic. There has been tremendous loss of human life and a great number of injuries. In addition, there has been great devastation to Haiti's weak infrastructure. Buildings have collapsed, telecommunications services have been greatly reduced, and the human and physical capacity of both international organizations with operations in Haiti and local organizations (such as hospitals and governmental organizations) in or near Port-au-Prince have been greatly impaired. It will be difficult to provide help to people in need in time to save them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HAS has been fortunate in that its operational facilities have survived the earthquake intact and are ready to help earthquake survivors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the hospital, and the patients in need whom they treat, are fortunate that there are people like you who have sacrificed $10 this month to ensure Haitian earthquake victims can be treated appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the next time you see a news report about the conditions in Haiti, rest assured you've made a positive difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving the world, ten dollars at a time,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. Please get those donations in if you are due and spread the word about our good work. It's easy to forward this letter on and appeal to others to be a part of the solution.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects-2010" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Adam Speaks At Vox Pop In Ny</title><link href="/news/2010/02/01/Adam-speaks-at-Vox-Pop-in-NY.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Adam Speaks At Vox Pop In Ny" /><published>2010-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2010/02/01/Adam-speaks-at-Vox-Pop-in-NY</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2010/02/01/Adam-speaks-at-Vox-Pop-in-NY.html"></content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Project 2010 01</title><link href="/projects-2010/2010/01/31/project-2010-01.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project 2010 01" /><published>2010-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2010-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/projects-2010/2010/01/31/project-2010-01</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects-2010/2010/01/31/project-2010-01.html">&lt;p&gt;Dear Friends:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to your January 2010 report for The $10 Club.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burundi is located in central Africa and contains 11 provinces with a rugged, high altitude terrain. Burundi suffered from civil war from 1993 to 2005, with high levels of insecurity resulting in a breakdown of general infrastructure. The civil war has left Burundi under-developed, with more than half of the population living on less than $1 a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burundi ranks in the bottom ten of the UN list of nations according to levels of human development and is ranked at the very bottom of the International Food Policy Institute's Global Hunger Index. Children under five in the country are particularly susceptible to insufficient dietary intake and, as a result, they suffer from weight loss and reduced growth. This is especially true among the country's estimated 230,000 orphans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burundi's impoverished citizens lack access to land and basic health and education services. Support for the poorest people is limited; the Government of Burundi is unable to cope with the increasing strain on its already inadequate resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because the Government and relief agencies have limited capacities, Burundi Orphan Relief, in conjunction with the Maranatha Mission Church, are working on the ground to support women and children especially orphans in Burundi. Self-sustainability, life-skills, and income generation are all promoted by the organization in the hope of turning the tide for the poorest of the poor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Burundi Orphan Relief, with whom we have worked in the past on micro-finance projects in the country, is looking to establish a new revenue-generation project in one of the most affected provinces, Bujumbura Rural. The project will work with an association of destitute, often widowed, women in the province, supporting their income generating abilities and increasing their purchasing power. And, as a result, contribute to support for orphans in the town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through our grant this month, a cooperative of 50 poor but newly empowered women will implement various income-generating activities and become self-reliant for their basic needs. A portion of the income generated will benefit the local orphan relief effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, 340 of us donated $3,400 to Burundi Orphan Relief to support their micro-finance project to support women and orphans in Burundi. Our grant will provide enough money to rent a room for six months to enable orphaned children to make clothes for sale, giving them a useful vocational skill in the process, as well as the tools needed to equip the shop; build a small shop to sell basic household needs and train local woman in building a small business; build and equip a small store for selling veterinary and agricultural products and provide necessary small business training for the women working there; and supply seeds and cultivation equipment to allow women to grow food for sale. The crop planting activities will be supervised by an agronomist with the University of Burundi. Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month's project will increase the self-reliance of women in need and generate income for the community. Maranatha Mission Church will give an association of 50 of the poorest women of Tankoni in Bujumbura Rural the land to build their shops. 50% of the income generated by the shop will be distributed among the association's beneficiaries and 50% of the income will be used to contribute to Burundi Orphans Relief's support of orphans in Bujumbura.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When successful, the project will result in the participating women being able to satisfy their basic household needs (food, clothes and education for their children). Women will have training that will help them permanently break the cycle of poverty. Burundi Orphan Relief's project in Bujumbura will receive a monthly contribution. And the clothes making shop will be able to cover the costs of the room rental after 6 months of the project implementation, providing long-term sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a standard line in the relief and humanitarian aid world that if you give a man a fish he eats for a day, but if you teach a man to fish he eats for a lifetime. I've always felt that teaching revenue-generation skills is great, but means little to someone who is literally starving to death or who has no medicines or mosquito nets or access to clean drinking water sometimes an immediate helping hand is needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when we're able to find opportunities for micro-finance projects, projects that are designed to bring stability to local communities and empower local people and save lives through the determination and hard work and newly-learned skills of the people who are suffering the most, we should jump on the chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's one of the many things that sets The $10 Club apart from other relief organizations the flexibility to respond to conditions and opportunities on the ground and help people directly and tangibly. In the process, we save lives every day without even realizing it. And thanks to this month's project in Burundi, we should save lives for months, and years, to come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving the world, ten dollars at a time,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS. At the end of 2007 we built a road in Haiti to connect a small, impoverished village with a hospital in the area. I'm working to identify possible projects in Haiti now, ensuring that our support will get to the people who need it the most.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="projects-2010" /><summary type="html">Dear Friends:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We Can All Be Philanthropists</title><link href="/news/2007/07/14/we-can-all-be-philanthropists.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Can All Be Philanthropists" /><published>2007-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2007-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>/news/2007/07/14/we-can-all-be-philanthropists</id><content type="html" xml:base="/news/2007/07/14/we-can-all-be-philanthropists.html">&lt;p&gt;From Mr Adam M. Roberts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sir, Bill Clinton is quite correct that &quot;we have to maximise private charity and private giving&quot; (report, July 2), and we should applaud his remarkable effort to promote global philanthropy. And as your New Philanthropy section shows, global leaders and well-endowed corporate leaders are investing appropriately in alleviating poverty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we must never assume someone else will solve the problems facing those millions of people without safe water or electricity, or who earn less than a dollar a day. Each of us can be a philanthropist with small personal sacrifices. Get two fewer gourmet coffees each month; buy a $20 bottle of wine with dinner instead of one costing $30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In return, we can put school uniforms on children needing an education, start microfinance programmes, ensure that families in at-risk areas have mosquito nets, bring safe drinking water to those without, and provide life-saving medicines to the most desperate people on earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's easy to turn away and expect governments, corporations and high-profile figures to take all the responsibility for poverty alleviation. But it is our responsibility, too. The question is not can we afford to say yes; but can we afford to say no?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;span&gt;Adam M. Roberts,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span&gt;President and Founder,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span&gt;The $10 Club,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Washington, DC 20007, US&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright The Financial Times Limited 2007&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="news" /><summary type="html">From Mr Adam M. Roberts.</summary></entry></feed>